# 哈喽 大家好
Hello, everybody.
# 上次做了个扬州炒饭
I made a Yangzhou fried rice last time.
# 那个火腿
Here is ham.
# 扬州炒饭一个炒饭用不完
It is too much for one fried rice.
# 我把这个拿回来 现在煮给我四伯爷吃
So I brought this back and I'm cooking it for my uncle.
# 听到说这个宣威火腿很好吃
I heard that this Xuanwei ham is delicious.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 还是多出名
So famous.
# 是很出名
It's famous.
# 这儿的两块就是我割来炒扬州炒饭了
I cut these two pieces to make Yangzhou fried rice.
# 这个火腿好多钱一斤安
How much is this ham costs?
# 算下来差不多60
It's almost 60 yuan per Jin (0.5kg).
# 哦哟 好贵哦
Oh, that's expensive.
# 我都只挑瘦的来炒饭 肥的有点腻
I only choose the lean part for the fried rice. The fat ones are a bit greasy.
# 你喜欢吃肥的嘛
You like the fat ones right?
# 肥瘦都可以
They are all fine.
# 我是随便
I'm okay with anything.
# 那我砍一坨哦
I'll cut a lump here.
# 砍嘛 一刀砍不断
Just do it, can you done by one chop?
# 一刀肯定砍不断
I'm sure it won't work by only one chop.
# 帮我逮都哈四伯爷
Help me to hold it, Uncle.
# 这个火腿有的可以生吃
Some of this Xuanwei ham can be eaten raw.
# 他说超过3年还是几年可以生吃
The vendor says the one with three or more years of mature can be eaten raw.
# 但是我个人觉得这个千万不要去生吃
But I personally don't think you should eat it raw.
# 好 现在我们就直接用来煮
Okay, now we'll just boil it directly.
# 之前其实我们已经吃过几次了
We've actually had it a few times before.
# 但是我四伯爷没有吃
But my Uncle haven't try it before.
# 这次就是拿下来煮给他老人家尝一下
This time I'm boiling it for him.
# 这个
Try this.
# 云南火腿跟我们四川腊肉有什么区别
To find what's the difference between Yunnan ham and our Sichuan cured meat.
# 这个太大块了 把它砍小一点 要不然煮很久
This lump is too big. Cut it down a bit, otherwise it'll take a long time to cook.
# 像那家人那样撒
Like the restaurant.
# 切小坨很了 切起不好看
Don't make it too small, it won't look good.
# 反正这在家里吃 大坨小坨都是在自己碗里的
It's okay, we eat it within family, big or small they're all in our bowls.
# 但是这个有个区别
There's a difference.
# 它不是那么咸
It's not that salty.
# 不像我们这里的腊肉那么咸
It's not as salty as our cured meat here.
# 如果说在我们这里四川搞得这么淡的话
If it's this low saltiness here in Sichuan...
# 我估计早就臭了
I think it will be gone bad.
# 它放不到这么久
It won't last long.
# 砍偏了
Missed.
# 来 王介平水加起弄来煮好
Here, Wang Jieping, add some water and boil it.
# 煮出来好像是跟我们本地的腊肉
Comparing it with our local cured meat.
# 你闻哈看
You smell it.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 不一样噶
It's different.
# 不一样
Different.
# 要淡点样
It's lighter.
# 要淡点噶
Definitely lighter.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 好 我们这个宣威腊肉已经煮好了
Okay, the Xuanwei ham is ready.
# 尝哈看
Try it.
# 伯娘感冒好了没有
Is Auntie getting over your cold?
# 你感冒好没
How's your cold?
# 没什么了
It's okay now.
# 没得事的 我这个感冒不存在的
It's okay. It's like never happened.
# 好了你就尝一下 没好你千万不要吃这个
Taste it. Don't eat it if you are still have cold.
# 嗯 好吃
Hmm, it's good.
# 这个腊肉是跟我们当地的腊肉不一样啊
This is different from our local cured meat.
# 还是要的噶
Still very good.
# 可以
Good.
# 但是这个要贵一点
But this is more expensive.
# 肯定了
Yes.
# 这种肥了弄来炒来吃
Those fat ones are better to make stir-fry.
# 这坨才是四伯爷 符合你的口味这坨
Uncle, this is the one that suits your taste.
# 你晓不晓得宣威火腿的这个肉的质量哦
What do you think about the quality of this meat for making Xuanwei ham?
# 土猪
Grain fed pig.
# 哦 对对对
Oh, yeah, yeah.
# 喂粮食的土猪
It's grain feeding pig.
# 都是喂的粮食 没加过饲料喂的
It's all grain, no extra feed.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 伯爷你看 大家可以看一下这一坨
Look at this, Uncle. Everybody take a look at this piece.
# 这个肥的地方要透光
This fat area needs to be light transparent.
# 然后瘦的地方这个颜色很红
And then the lean part need to be this red color.
# 很漂亮
It's beautiful.
# 好 这坨我就切大一点哈
Okay, bigger pieces for this lump.
# 要的啊
Yes.
# 符合四伯爷的口味
Uncle just loves it.
# 这个骨头上面的肉更香
Actually the meat near the bone tastes better.
# 这儿把肉切下来骨头拿给狗吃
Here, cut off the meat and give the bones to the dog.
# 不拿给狗吃了 浪费了
I'm not giving it to the dog. It's a waste.
# 诶呀 好香哦噶
Oh, it smells so good.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 那你拿来宰起撒
Okay, cut it up.
# 这个真是没想到啊
That's a surprise.
# 这个骨头上面的肉更好吃
The meat is better near the bone.
# 肯定了
Sure.
# 放在旁边
Put it on the plate.
# 好 吃饭
Okay, let's eat.
# 好 开饭
# 我去洗一下手 四伯爷你端一下
I'm going to wash my hands, Uncle, you take this.
# 这个腊肉是要好吃点
This does taste better.
# 够了
That's enough.
# 吃饭吃饭
Eat! Eat!
# 你还在啃(骨头）啊
You're still chewing the bones?
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 伯娘真的骨头上面的肉比边上的肉好吃
The meat on the bones is better than the meat on the sides.
# 好吃 安逸得很
It's delicious. It's very nice.
# 是不是好吃
Isn't it delicious?
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 但是我觉得肥的地方不好吃
But I don't think the fat part is good.
# 好香哦
Good.
# 肥的地方腻
The fat part is greasy.
# 对于我们年轻人来说肥的地方有点腻
It's a bit greasy for us youngsters.
# 对于我伯爷来说
But not for my uncle.
# 我就喜欢吃那种
That's what I like to eat.
# 符合他的胃口
It's exactly to his liking.
# 然后我觉得这个骨头旁边的肉更香
And I think the meat next to the bone is better.
# 吃块腊肉
Let me have a piece of cured meat.
# 火腿不叫腊肉哈
Ham, is not regular cured meat.
# 吃块火腿
Have a piece of ham.
# 我就吃这个火腿的肥的
I'll take the fat one.
# 在我们四川通通都是腊肉
In Sichuan, all those will consider as cured meat.
# 管你什么哪里的火腿
People don't care where the ham came from.
# 安逸这个
This is nice.
# 好安逸嘛 亮锃锃的
It's so nice and shiny.
# 腊肉还可以
This is good.
# 下次炒扬州炒饭给你吃
I'll cook Yangzhou fried rice for you next time.
# 要的啊
Yes.
# 嗯
Hmm.
# 就是个炒饭
It's just fried rice.
# 你把饭煮起就是
You just cook the rice.
# 要的要的
Yes, yes.
# 要冷的哦
I need the rice to be cold.
# 好嘛 早点煮来冷到撒
Okay, I will cook it early and let it get cold.
# 啊
Good.
# 好 本期视频到这里
Okay, that's it for this video.
# 拜拜
Bye-bye